Phillip Lee

Houston, TX, 77035 832-478-8169 phileetech@gmail.com

IT Professional with 6+ years of experience in developing web and business intelligence solutions for diverse industry clients. Highly instrumental in all phases of the SDLC, with expertise in algorithms and data structures. Successful in developing bespoke solutions, optimizing business procedures, processes, and productivity.

TECHNOLOGY

Frontend: React.js, Angular.js, Javascript, Typescript

Programming: Python, Node.js, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX

Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Laravel, Django, Flask, Express, Nest.js

DBMS: MySQL, Postgres, SQL Server, MongoDB

CI/CD: Git, GitHub, Gitlab

Cloud: AWS (EC2, S3, Lamda), GCP, Heroku

Systems: Linux/Apache, Windows Server/IIS, Docker

Processes: Agile, Scrum, Requirements, Design, Development, Database

Administration, Testing, Deployment, Maintenance, Documentation, ETL

Process, Content Management Systems

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CASESTRY

Software engineer, January 2022 – September 2022

- Responsible for developing and maintaining Imagery Creation System based React.js frontend, Python backend
- Designed and built the API, and reusable modules in Python
- Built the components and pages in *ATOMIC* design patterns in React.js

CAPITAL ONE

Software Engineer, May 2019 - December 2021

- Responsible for developing and maintaining React.js frontend, Cryptocurrency App
- Built the RESTful API and modules and classes in Python/Django
- Deployed in AWS EC2, Used AWS S3 for the website assets storage
- Worked in the agile team, working on tasks in weekly sprints

BAXTER INTERNATIONAL INC.

Software Engineer, Feb 2018 - April 2019

 Responsible for building and maintaining the React.js frontend, Ruby on Rails backend the Project Management System for Agile Teams

- Built the reusable modules and views in Ruby on Rails
- Integrated the settlement function for clients and dev teams
- Worked in the team environment running weekly sprints

BORALEX

Software Engineer, July 2016 – Jan 2018

- Responsible for building HTML, Javascript, CSS frontend, and PHP, Laravel backend
- Renewal and redesigned the wordpress blog website of the company
- Redesigned the layout of the frontend with HTML, Javascript, CSS
- Improved user satisfaction scores by 3%

FOUR SEASONS

Software Engineer, January 2016 – June 2016

- Responsible for building and redesigning the four-seasons shop website in Shopify
- Redesigned the layout of the website and added the customized functions in the Checkout process
- Improved user satisfaction scores by 5%

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Dallas

Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering, March 2014